YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 3. National Administrative Office
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IV. DATA AND STATISTICS
  - Department
    - Integrated Management Information System "YWNet, YW Link"
      - Proposal, Peat, Marwick, Mitchell & Co., 1982 (Box 232, Folder 17)
      - Phase I, Evaluation Laboratory, 17 Sep 1982
        - Volume 1 (Box 232, Folder 18)
        - Volume 2 (Box 233, Folder 1)
      - Phase I, Final Report, Jan 1983 (Box 233, Folder 2)
    - Job descriptions, 1944-45 (Box 233, Folder 3)
    - Program Bank, 1973-76 (Box 233, Folder 4)
    - Reference materials, 1949-58, n.d. (Box 233, Folder 5)
    - Reports
      - General (Box 233, Folder 6)
      - Monthly, 1955-60 (Box 233, Folder 7)
  - Forms and Guidelines
    - General, 1939-60 (Box 233, Folder 8-10)
    - Annual Statistical Report Forms (with materials re periodic form revisions) (Box 233)
      - 1947, 1955/56-1959/60; 1972-75/76 (Box 233, Folder 11-17)
      - 1977/78-82 (Box 234, Folder 1-8)
    - Automated Services in Member YWCAs: questionnaire, 1987 (Box 234, Folder 9)
    - Certification (aka Accreditation) and Basic Standards (aka Affiliation)
      - General, 1954-58, 1963-66 (Box 234, Folder 10-11)
      - Basic Standards Report: notes and summary, 1952, 1957 (Box 234, Folder 12)
      - Community YWCAs
        - Analysis of Basic Standards Reports, 1958-61 (Box 234, Folder 13)
        - Lists and reports, 1956, 1958-61 (Box 234, Folder 14-17)
      - Student YWCAs
        - Analysis of Basic Standards Reports, 1958-61: Student Associations (Box 234, Folder 18)
        - Correspondence, 1959-61 (Box 234, Folder 19)
        - Lists and reports
          - 1955-59 (Box 234, Folder 20-21)
          - 1960-61 (Box 235, Folder 1)
    - Community Studies, [see National Services Division for earlier examples]
      - Community Wise, notebook for gathering information about a community, 1947 (Box 235, Folder 2)
      - Look Beneath the Surface of the Community, work tool for gathering information about a community, 1960, 1968, 1974 (Box 235, Folder 3)
      - Financial Development Questionnaire, 1997 (Box 235, Folder 4)
    - "Complete Manual of Directions for the YWCA Method of Analyzing Costs by Programs: A Handbook for use by directors of cost studies in local YWCAs," 1959: manual and digest of manual (Box 235, Folder 5)
    - Record Keeping, 1951-83, n.d. (Box 235, Folder 6-7)
  - Publications
    - Directory of the YWCA of the USA
      - 1888, 1918, 1920, 1947, 1951-87 (Box 235, Folder 8-11)
      - 1991-98 (Box 236, Folder 1-2)
    - Housing and Residences Directories, 1949, 1981, 1984 (Box 236, Folder 3)
    - Statistical compilations from annual reports of Community Associations
      - Handbook of the YWCA [includes essays on program and other general information], 1910, 1914, 1919 (Box 236, Folder 4-6)
      - Directory and Statistical Report, 1908-10 (Box 236, Folder 7-8)
      - Year Book 9-10 1910/11
        - 1911/12-1916/17 (Box 237, Folder 1-6)
        - 1916-19 (Box 238, Folder 1-2)
      - "Compilation of Statistics," 1937-38 (Box 238, Folder 3)
      - Figures Talk Back!, 1939-1958/59 (Box 238, Folder 4-8)
      - Tallies and Trends, 1961-71 (Box 239, Folder 1-3)
      - The Print Out
        - 1970/71-1978/79 (Box 239, Folder 4-6)
        - 1979/80-86 (Box 240, Folder 1-2)
      - Statistical Report of the YWCA of the USA, 1996 (Box 240, Folder 3)
      - How the YWCA Makes a Difference: Statistical Report from the National Association of YWCAs, 1994, 1997 (Box 240, Folder 4)
    - The Tally Sheet, 1942-61 (Box 240, Folder 5)
    - Feminine Figures: Selected Facts About American Women and Girls, 1968-72 (Box 240, Folder 6)
    - Research Update, 1989-90 (Box 240, Folder 7)
  - Studies and Reports
    - Miscellaneous, 1954-66 (Box 240, Folder 8)
    - Buildings and Facilities
      - General, 1925-54 (Box 240, Folder 9)
      - Cafeteria and Food Service, 1953-59 (Box 240, Folder 10)
      - Camps and Summer Programs, 1940-61 (Box 240, Folder 11-12)
      - Gymnasiums and Pools, 1951-63 (Box 240, Folder 13)
      - Residences/Housing
        - 1947-48 (Box 240, Folder 14)
        - 1953-72 (Box 241, Folder 1)
    - Community YWCAs
      - Annual Summary of Studies of, or of Interest to Community YWCAs, 1956-60 (Box 241, Folder 2-3)
      - Decentralized Program, 1954-63 (Box 241, Folder 4)
      - Index of Association Size and Complexity, 1978 (Box 241, Folder 5)
      - Local Studies summaries, 1955-59 (Box 241, Folder 6)
      - Population, 1949-61 (Box 241, Folder 7)
      - Statistical reports, 1954-1963/64, 1970/71 (Box 242, Folder 1-6)
    - Conventions and Conferences, 1961-85 (Box 242, Folder 7)
    - District YWCAs, 1953-59 (Box 242, Folder 8)
    - Financial
      - Analysis of 1961 Financial Statements of Community YWCAs, Nov 1962 (Box 242, Folder 9)
      - Cost Analysis, Pilot Study to develop methods, Detroit YWCA,1956-59 (Box 242, Folder 10-12)
      - Fund Campaigns for Facilities, 1954-58 (Box 242, Folder 13)
      - Inquiry on Membership and Activity Fees, 1956-57 (Box 242, Folder 14)
      - Membership Dues reports, 1956/57-1958/59 (Box 242, Folder 15)
      - Report on Activity Fees in Community YWCAs, 1958 (Box 242, Folder 16)
    - Girl Scouts' public opinion survey, 1957 (Box 243, Folder 1)
    - Goals for the Decade and Objectives for the 1979-82 Triennium: report, 1980-81 (Box 243, Folder 2)
    - Membership
      - Industrial Women Workers and Women Service Workers in the YWCA, 1956 (Box 243, Folder 3)
      - Statistical report, 1951 (Box 243, Folder 4)
      - Study to Improve Membership Practices, 1958-59 (Box 243, Folder 5)
      - Association Responses to Membership Development Questionnaire, 1984 (Box 243, Folder 6)
    - Men, Boys, and Families in the YWCA, and Family Life Education, 1954-57 (Box 243, Folder 7-8)
    - New Organization/Expansion, 1953-60 (Box 243, Folder 9)
    - Personnel
      - Inquiry on Selected Personnel Practices in Community YWCAs, 1956 (Box 243, Folder 10)
      - Residence Directors, 1951-60 (Box 243, Folder 11)
      - Retirement Fund participation, 1959-61 (Box 243, Folder 12)
      - Salary Study, 1958 (Box 243, Folder 13)
      - Staff Qualifications in Community YWCAs, 1958 (Box 243, Folder 14)
      - Study of the District YWCA Executive Director's Job, 1956-58 (Box 243, Folder 15)
      - Study of Why Staff Leave the YWCA, 1957-59 (Box 243, Folder 16)
      - Volunteer Training, 1956-57 (Box 243, Folder 17)
    - Program
      - Community YWCA Program in 24 Selected Subject Areas, 1961-62 (Box 243, Folder 18)
      - Home Women's Groups in the YWCA, 1948 (Box 243, Folder 19)
      - Services to Public Housing residents, 1994 (Box 243, Folder 20)
      - Sex Education, program summary, 1962 (Box 243, Folder 21)
      - Student YWCA Program in 30 Selected Subject Areas, 1963 (Box 243, Folder 22)
      - Teenage Program Study, 1958-60 (Box 243, Folder 23)
      - Trends in Adult Programs, 1956-59 (Box 244, Folder 1)
    - Public Policy
      - Labor Standards for Women Workers, 1959 (Box 244, Folder 2)
      - Unemployment questionnaire, 1961 (Box 244, Folder 3)
    - Racial Inclusiveness in Community and Student YWCAs, 1956-60 (Box 245, Folder 1-3)
    - Racial/Ethnic and Age Diversity in the YWCA, 1975-76 (Box 245, Folder 4)
    - Record Keeping
      - Experiment for Gathering Facts re Nativity, Race, and Religion, 1953-54 (Box 245, Folder 5)
      - Membership Registration, 1950 (Box 245, Folder 6)
      - Recording and Reporting, New York Interborough Commission of YWCAs study, 1948 (Box 245, Folder 7)
    - Registered YWCAs, 1952-61 (Box 245, Folder 8)
    - Religion, misc. studies, 1944-59 (Box 245, Folder 9)
    - Student YWCAs: Statistical Reports, 1950-61 (Box 245, Folder 10-19)
    - YMCA-YWCA relationships, 1952-76 (Box 245, Folder 20)
- SERIES V. LIBRARY AND ARCHIVES
  - General and history, 1986-99, n.d. (Box 246, Folder 1)
  - Library
    - General, 1938-97, n.d. (Box 246, Folder 2-3)
    - Library committee, 1934-60 (Box 246, Folder 4)
    - Cataloguing, 1968-79, n.d. (Box 246, Folder 5)
    - Furniture and equipment, 1959-60 (Box 246, Folder 6)
    - Leadership Development Center Library, 1981-83, n.d. (Box 246, Folder 7)
    - Office forms, n.d. (Box 246, Folder 8)
    - Publications
      - Bibliographies, 1964-86, n.d. (Box 246, Folder 9)
      - Have You Heard About.. ., 1968-72 (Box 246, Folder 10)
      - Book Notes, 1976-80 (Box 246, Folder 11)
      - New Library Books: Purchase and Gifts, 1978-82 (Box 246, Folder 12)
    - YWCA historical publications collection, 1984, n.d. (Box 246, Folder 13)
  - Archives
    - General and History
      - General, 1980-2000 (Box 246, Folder 14-16)
      - "'Without documents no history,' Sources and Strategies for Researching the YWCA" by Nancy Robertson and Elizabeth Norris, in Men and Women Adrift: The YMCA and YWCA in the City, 1853-1980 (Box 246)
        - Drafts and notes (Box 246, Folder 17)
        - Correspondence, 1992-96 (Box 246, Folder 18)
      - History of National Board files
        - General, 1921-87, n.d. (Box 246, Folder 19)
        - Document clerk's index to "Record File," circa 1963 (Box 247, Folder 1)
        - Microfilm, 1963-2001 (Box 247, Folder 2)
        - Records management, 1990 (Box 247, Folder 3)
      - Records at other repositories
        - General, 1957-92, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 4)
        - Social Welfare History Archives, University of Minnesota
          - General, 1965-93 (Box 247, Folder 5)
          - USO, 1985-99 (Box 247, Folder 6)
          - Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College, [see also Library general, 1963]
            - General, 1964-2001 (Box 247, Folder 7-8)
            - Preparation for transfer of Archives, 2002 (Box 247, Folder 9)
      - World YWCA Archives, 1943-89, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 10)
    - Committee/Department
      - General, 1972-2000 (Box 247, Folder 11)
      - Archives Committee, 1974-77 (Box 247, Folder 12)
      - Office forms, 1971-89, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence
        - Re Ceremonials of Common Days by Abbie Graham, 1980-81 (Box 247, Folder 14)
        - Re Notable American Women, 1977-79 (Box 247, Folder 15)
        - Reference [sample], 1990-97, n.d. (Box 247, Folder 16-17)
        - Surveys of YWCA historical records holdings (Box 247)
        - General, 1976-94 (Box 248, Folder 1-2)
          - Women's History Sources, 1975-78 (Box 248, Folder 3)
      - Publications
        - Leaflets, 1978-87 (Box 248, Folder 4)
        - "Non-scholarly sketches," 1995-98 (Box 248, Folder 5)
        - Archives box in YWCA Interchange, 1978-83 (Box 248, Folder 6)
    - Exhibits
      - General and miscellaneous, 1968-94, n.d. (Box 248, Folder 7)
      - Children's books depicting a racially integrated America, Oct 1965 (Box 248, Folder 8)
      - 60th Anniversary of the National Board, 1966 (Box 248, Folder 9)
      - "Supporting Each Other: Third World Women and the YWCA" and "The Diverse Community: A Force in the Life of the Association from 1900 to the Interracial Charter," 1981
        - General and photocopies (Box 248, Folder 10)
        - Caption cards (Box 248, Folder 11)
      - Focus on South Africa, All Staff Program, 1985 (Box 248, Folder 12)
      - History of social work with groups, 1985 (Box 248, Folder 13)
      - YWCA History, Orientation for New National Staff, 1990 (Box 248, Folder 14)
      - 135th Anniversary "Women First for 135 Years, 1855-1993," 1995 (Box 248, Folder 15)
      - Suffrage,1995
        - Correspondence and mock-ups (Box 248, Folder 16)
        - Research (Box 248, Folder 17)
      - "The Struggle for the Union at the YWCA: Looking Back 60 Years," 1999 (Box 248, Folder 18)
    - Holdings
      - Lists
        - General and miscellaneous, 1982-97, n.d. (Box 248, Folder 19)
        - Artifacts (Box 248, Folder 20-21)
        - Dissertations and theses re the YWCA, 1997, n.d. (Box 249, Folder 1)
        - Microfilm inventory, 1978 (Box 249, Folder 2-4)
        - Minutes and reports (Box 249, Folder 5)
        - Photographs (Box 249, Folder 6)
        - YWCA Publications (Box 249, Folder 7)
      - Subject index to YWCA pamphlets (Box 249, Folder 8)
      - Lead file (potential donors), A-Z, 1972-89 (Box 249, Folder 9)
      - Case files (=Donor files, Acquisition files)
        - Miscellaneous, A-Z (Box 249, Folder 10)
        - Abel, Barbara (Box 249, Folder 11)
        - Adams, Charlotte (Box 249, Folder 12)
        - American School of Languages and Art (YWCA of Turkey) (Box 249, Folder 13)
        - Audio-Visual Collection (Box 249, Folder 14)
        - Augustine, Hazel (Box 249, Folder 15)
        - Boyd, Kate Hillis (Box 249, Folder 16)
        - Buildings
          - General (Box 249, Folder 17)
          - 600 Lexington Ave. "Reminiscences Collection II" (Box 249, Folder 18)
        - Business and Professional Work (Box 249, Folder 19)
        - Calkins, Gladys Gilkey (Box 249, Folder 20)
        - Camps (Box 249, Folder 21)
        - China (Box 249, Folder 22)
        - Clarke, Elizabeth Dodge Huntington (Box 250, Folder 1)
        - Communications Unit (Box 250, Folder 2)
        - Community Division/Member Association Services (Box 250, Folder 3)
        - Community Associations
          - City of New York (Box 250, Folder 4)
          - Mt. Vernon, NY (Box 250, Folder 5)
          - Registered YWCA groups (Box 250, Folder 6)
          - Suffolk County, NY (Box 250, Folder 7)
        - Comptroller (Box 250, Folder 8)
        - Convention and Conference Office (Box 250, Folder 9)
        - Elliot, Grace Loucks (Box 250, Folder 10)
        - Executive Office (Box 250, Folder 11)
        - Financial Development (Box 250, Folder 12)
        - Genne, Elizabeth (Box 250, Folder 13)
        - Girl Reserve (Box 250, Folder 14)
        - Graham, Abbie (Box 250, Folder 15)
        - Health, Physical Education, and Recreation (Box 250, Folder 16)
        - Hendee, Elizabeth Russell (Box 250, Folder 17)
        - Herring, Elizabeth (Box 250, Folder 18)
        - Industrial work (Box 250, Folder 19)
        - Ingraham, Mary S. (Box 250, Folder 20)
        - Jache, Lida S. (Box 250, Folder 21)
        - James, Genevieve (Box 250, Folder 22)
        - Johns, Elizabeth (Box 250, Folder 23)
        - Lerrigo, Edith (Box 250, Folder 24)
        - Long, Lillian Louise (Box 250, Folder 25)
        - Lyon, Sarah S. (Box 250, Folder 26)
        - McCulloch, Rhoda (Box 250, Folder 27)
        - Meares, Carrie E. (Box 250, Folder 28)
        - Membership/Leadership Development Unit (Box 250, Folder 29)
        - Memorabilia [Artifacts]
          - General (Box 250, Folder 30)
          - Awards and certificates (Box 250, Folder 31)
        - Miller, Hazel Vernon (Box 250, Folder 32)
        - Minutes and Reports (Box 250, Folder 33)
        - Music Program (Box 250, Folder 34)
        - National Association of Employed Officers of the YWCA (Box 250, Folder 35)
        - Oral History Collection (Box 250, Folder 36)
        - Photographs (Box 250, Folder 37)
        - Posters (Box 250, Folder 38)
        - Precursor Organizations (Box 250, Folder 39)
        - Public Affairs Program (Box 250, Folder 40)
        - Publications (Box 250, Folder 41)
        - Records Files (Central file) (Box 250, Folder 42)
        - Records File II (Box 250, Folder 43)
        - Rice, Anna Virena (Box 250, Folder 44)
        - Robinson, Marion (8 Women of the YWCA) (Box 250, Folder 45)
        - Scrapbooks, miscellaneous (Box 250, Folder 46)
        - Sharpley, Lilian ('A History of the National Board's Work with Business and Professional Women') (Box 250, Folder 47)
        - Southard, Helen (Box 250, Folder 48)
        - Spellmann, Dorothea (Box 250, Folder 49)
        - Stauffer, Norma (Box 250, Folder 50)
        - Student work (Box 251, Folder 1)
        - Training Programs (Box 251, Folder 2)
        - United Service Organizations (USO) (Box 251, Folder 3)
        - World Relations/Foreign Division
          - Records (Box 251, Folder 4)
          - Reminiscences Collection I (Box 251, Folder 5)
        - York, Lena (Box 251, Folder 6)
        - Wygal, Winnifred (Box 251, Folder 7)
        - Young, Louise (Box 251, Folder 8)
        - World War I
          - War Work Council (Box 251, Folder 9)
          - Polish Gray Samaritans (Box 251, Folder 10)
          - Individuals, miscellaneous (Box 251, Folder 11)
      - Accession forms by accession number (Box 252, Folder 1-8)
      - Card index to collections (Box 253)
    - Projects
      - Oral History (various), 1966-89, n.d. (Box 254, Folder 1)
      - Archival Research Project, 1975 (Box 254, Folder 2)
      - National Board Archives Project (Box 254)
        - General, 1976-79, n.d. (Box 254, Folder 3-4)
        - National Endowment for the Humanities grant: "A New Resource for Scholars: the YWCA Archives"
          - Application, 1976 (Box 254, Folder 5)
          - Final Report, 1978 (Box 254, Folder 6)
        - Community Association Records
          - General, 1978-91 (Box 254, Folder 7)
          - International Institutes Project, Immigration History Research Center, University of Minnesota, 1975-78 (Box 254, Folder 8)
          - YWCA of the City of New York, 1975-2001, n.d. (Box 254, Folder 9)
          - YWCA of Metropolitan Denver, Colorado Historical Society, 1991 (Box 254, Folder 10)
          - YWCA of Mt. Vernon, New York, Social Welfare History Archives, University of Minnesota, 1970-72 (Box 254, Folder 11)
      - Publication, The Joy of Service: Memoirs of Elizabeth Dodge Huntington Clarke, 1976-80 (Box 254, Folder 12)
      - History of YWCA Foreign Service
        - Reminiscences from X-Fs
          - General, 1980-81 (Box 254, Folder 13)
          - Manuscripts and correspondence, A-Z (Box 254, Folder 14-18)
        - Emissaries: The Overseas Work of the American YWCA, 1895-1970: correspondence and general, 1981-95 (Box 255, Folder 1)
      - President portraits gallery (proposed), 1988-94, n.d. (Box 255, Folder 2)
      - History of the YWCA-Later Period (proposed), 1990-91 (Box 255, Folder 3)
      - Library and Archives Project (did not receive funding)
        - General, 1994-95 (Box 255, Folder 4)
        - Proposal to National Endowment for the Humanities, 1994 (Box 255, Folder 5)
      - Digital archives project: IBM grant, 2000-01 (Box 255, Folder 6)
      - Milestones Project, 2001 (did not receive funding) (Box 255, Folder 7)
    - YWCA History subject files
      - General
        - Chronologies (Box 255, Folder 8)
        - Community Associations (Box 255, Folder 9)
        - Landmark dates/firsts (Box 255, Folder 10)
        - Lists of officers (Box 255, Folder 11)
        - Miscellaneous subjects (Box 255, Folder 12)
        - Short histories (Box 255, Folder 13)
        - Trivia (Box 255, Folder 14)
      - American Indians (Box 256, Folder 1)
      - Biography
        - General (Box 256, Folder 2)
        - Edna St. Vincent Millay (Box 256, Folder 3)
      - Black women in the YWCA (Box 256, Folder 4)
      - Buildings
        - General (Box 256, Folder 5)
        - Chautauqua, New York (Box 256, Folder 6)
        - Community Associations (Box 256, Folder 7)
        - Buildings with historical landmark status: YWCA of the City of New York, 7 East 15th St and 14-16 East 16th St., Ladies' Mile Historic District (Box 256, Folder 8)
        - Julia Morgan, architect
          - General and biography (Box 256, Folder 9)
          - Correspondence with biographer, Sara Holmes Boutelle (Box 256, Folder 10)
          - Reference correspondence (Box 256, Folder 11)
          - Asilomar Conference Grounds (Box 256, Folder 12)
          - California YWCAs (Box 256, Folder 13)
          - Other YWCAS (Box 256, Folder 14)
          - Pan-Pacific Exposition (Box 256, Folder 15)
          - Photocopies of images of Julia Morgan buildings (Box 256, Folder 16)
        - National Headquarters
          - General (Box 256, Folder 17)
          - 600 Lexington Ave., New York City (Box 256, Folder 18)
        - Washington Cathedral window (Box 256, Folder 19)
      - Cafeterias (Box 256, Folder 20)
      - China (Box 256, Folder 21)
      - Christmas, "Hanging of the Greens" (Box 256, Folder 22)
      - Clothing and uniforms (Box 256, Folder 23)
      - Conventions (Box 256, Folder 24)
      - Copyright (Box 257, Folder 1)
      - Czechoslovakia (Box 257, Folder 2)
      - Education and Training (Box 257, Folder 3)
      - Employed women (Box 257, Folder 4)
      - Expositions and World Fairs (Box 257, Folder 5)
      - Foreign program (Box 257, Folder 6)
      - Health, physical education, recreation, and sex education (Box 257, Folder 7)
      - International Institutes (Box 257, Folder 8)
      - Jewelry (Box 257, Folder 9)
      - Libraries in the YWCA (Box 257, Folder 10)
      - Membership (Box 257, Folder 11)
      - Memorials to YWCA workers (Box 257, Folder 12)
      - Music (including "Follow the Gleam") (Box 257, Folder 13)
      - Posters
        - General (Box 257, Folder 14)
        - World War I (Box 257, Folder 15)
      - Predecessor organizations (Box 257, Folder 16)
      - Publications and Womans Press (Box 257, Folder 17)
      - Racial Justice policies and practices (Box 257, Folder 18)
      - Residences and Rooms Registry (Box 257, Folder 19)
      - Sexual orientation (Box 257, Folder 20)
      - Students (Box 258, Folder 1)
      - Suffrage (Box 258, Folder 2)
      - Symbols
        - General (Box 258, Folder 3)
        - Codes, mottos, and seals (Box 258, Folder 4)
        - Community Associations (Box 258, Folder 5)
        - Logo and proper use of YWCA symbols (Box 258, Folder 6)
        - Magazine articles (Box 258, Folder 7)
        - Monograms, line art (Box 258, Folder 8)
        - Predecessor organizations (Box 258, Folder 9)
        - Teen Age/Girl Reserve (Box 258, Folder 10)
        - Triangle
          - General (Box 258, Folder 11)
          - YMCA (Box 258, Folder 12)
      - Teen Age and Younger Girls (includes Girl Reserve) (Box 258, Folder 13)
      - Traveller's Aid (Box 258, Folder 14)
      - Trustees (Box 258, Folder 15)
      - War work
        - General (Box 258, Folder 16)
        - World War I, Publicity (Box 258, Folder 17)
        - World War I, War Work Council Reports (Box 258, Folder 18)
      - Women's rights (Box 258, Folder 19)
      - World YWCA (Box 258, Folder 20)
- SERIES VI. PUBLICITY
  - General and History
    - General, 1927-97, n.d. (Box 259, Folder 1-2)
    - The Advertising Council: correspondence and general, 1978-84 (Box 259, Folder 3)
    - Feature article: "A Woman's Place is Everywhere!," 1961-62 (Box 259, Folder 4)
    - Job Corps-YWCA Extension Residence Program, 1967-75 (Box 259, Folder 5)
    - Merchandise, 1959-98, n.d. (Box 259, Folder 6)
    - Survey re use of Chapels in YWCA buildings (proposed article), 1949 (Box 259, Folder 7)
    - YWCA "Fact Sheets," 1977-2000, n.d. (Box 259, Folder 8)
  - Committees/Departments/Bureau Minutes
    - Publicity Committee: minutes, 1913-21 (Box 259, Folder 9-13)
    - Public Relations Committee, 1942-47 (Box 259, Folder 14)
    - Public Information Committee, 1948-61 (Box 259, Folder 15-16)
    - Bureau of Communications (Box 259, Folder 17-18)
      - 1961-64 (Box 259, Folder 19)
      - 1965-74 (Box 260, Folder 1-2)
    - Public Relations Committee, 1974-82 (Box 260, Folder 3)
  - Programs and Projects
    - Film: "To All Who Believe in Youth,": correspondence, scripts, etc., 1948-53 (Box 260, Folder 4-5)
    - National YWCA Week
      - 1947, 1956-59, 1970, 1973-74, 1976-85, 1987-89 (Box 260, Folder 6-10)
      - 1990-91 (Box 261, Folder 1)
    - Organizational Identity Program and new logo, 1987-88 (Box 261, Folder 2)
  - Publications
    - General YWCA information
      - Brochures and pamphlets, circa 1910-2001, n.d. (Box 261, Folder 3-5)